[
  {
    "id": "01",
    "question": "JSON stands for _______",
    "options": [
      "JavaScript Object Notation",
      "Java Object Notation",
      "JavaScript Object Normalization",
      "JavaScript Object-Oriented Notation"
    ],
    "answer": "JavaScript Object Notation"
  },
  {
    "id": "02",
    "question": " JSON is a _____ for storing and transporting data",
    "options": ["xml format", "text format", "JavaScript", "php format"],
    "answer": "text format"
  },
  {
    "id": "03",
    "question": "Who is the creator of JSON?",
    "options": [
      "Alvin Alexander",
      "Rasmus Lerdorf",
      "Douglas Crockford",
      "Jesse James Garrett"
    ],
    "answer": "Douglas Crockford"
  },
  {
    "id": "04",
    "question": "In the JSON syntax, data is separated by _____",
    "options": ["Semicolons", "Colons", "nCommas", "Hypen"],
    "answer": "Commas"
  },
  {
    "id": "05",
    "question": "Which is the correct symbol to insert a comment in JSON?",
    "options": [
      "//",
      "/*…*/",
      "<!-- … -->",
      "JSON doesn't support the comments"
    ],
    "answer": "JSON doesn't support the comments"
  },
  {
    "id": "06",
    "question": "A common use of JSON is ________.",
    "options": [
      "to update data into the database",
      "to retrieve data from the database",
      "to exchange data to/from a web server",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "to exchange data to/from a web server"
  },
  {
    "id": "07",
    "question": "Which function is used to convert text into a JavaScript object?",
    "options": [
      "JSON.parse()",
      "string.parse()",
      "object.parse()",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "JSON.parse()"
  },
  {
    "id": "08",
    "question": "Which function is used to convert a JavaScript object into a string?",
    "options": [
      "JSON.string()",
      "JSON.stringify()",
      "JSON.ToString()",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "JSON.stringify()"
  },
  {
    "id": "09",
    "question": "JSON array elements can be access by ___.",
    "options": ["Name", "Key", "Value", "Index"],
    "answer": "Index"
  },
  {
    "id": "10",
    "question": "Which number types are available in the JavaScript but not supported in the JSON?",
    "options": [
      "Fractional and Rational",
      "Infinity and Rational",
      "Rational and Irrational",
      "Infinity and NaN"
    ],
    "answer": "Infinity and NaN"
  }
]
